<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Anna&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.kempest.site/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Anna&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kempest.site/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to make a blog in R blogdown and Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://www.kempest.site/2021/03/04/how-to-make-a-blog-in-r-blogdown-and-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kempest.site/2021/03/04/how-to-make-a-blog-in-r-blogdown-and-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>This post is made for and also published in the blog of community women.code(be).
The purpose of this tutorial This is a quick tutorial on how to create a blog with R and deploy it to Github Pages. It is useful for anyone who wants to make a static website in markdown and host it for free. It can be also helpful if you just want to get some practice with markdown or R markdown, learn web site basics and R programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlation analysis limitations in examples</title>
      <link>https://www.kempest.site/2020/07/15/correlation-analysis-limitations-in-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kempest.site/2020/07/15/correlation-analysis-limitations-in-examples/</guid>
      <description>Preview Correlation analysis is a common method for studying a relationship between two variables and data exploration. Here I do not intend to explain in much details the theoretical part of the correlation analysis but I want to provide several practical examples where this method is applicable or not. For that purpose, I will generate simple datasets in R, create plots and discuss the obtained results.
If you are more interested in the theory of correlation analysis or tools for correlation analsis in R or other programming languages, I would refer to another works then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog</title>
      <link>https://www.kempest.site/2020/07/05/about-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kempest.site/2020/07/05/about-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>Content of this blog I am starting this blog to share my knowledge in mathematics, modelling, statistics, programming (mainly in R and Python) and data science. During all the time of my studying from bachelor to PhD I always had an inspiring cases that really worth sharing. That is why this blog exists and that reminds me about Leo Tolstoy’s quote “You should write only when you cannot help but write” (in his diary from October 19th, 1909) and this is truly my story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
