<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Anna&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.kempest.site/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Anna&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kempest.site/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to make blog in R blogdown and Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://www.kempest.site/2021/03/04/how-to-make-blog-in-rblogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kempest.site/2021/03/04/how-to-make-blog-in-rblogdown/</guid>
      <description>This post is made for the blog of community women.code(be).
The purpose of this tutorial Did you ever think about making your own website or personal blog easily and for free? Or maybe you want to learn some web development basics? Then this tutorial might be interesting for you. Below we will create a static website in markdown with R programming language and deploy it to Github Pages. Don’t be afraid if you are not familiar with R or markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlation analysis limitations in examples</title>
      <link>https://www.kempest.site/2020/07/15/correlation-analysis-limitations-in-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kempest.site/2020/07/15/correlation-analysis-limitations-in-examples/</guid>
      <description>Preview Correlation analysis is a common method for studying a relationship between two variables and data exploration. Here I do not intend to explain in much details the theoretical part of the correlation analysis but I want to provide several practical examples where this method is applicable or not. For that purpose, I will generate simple datasets in R, create plots and discuss the obtained results.
If you are more interested in the theory of correlation analysis or tools for correlation analsis in R or other programming languages, I would refer to another works then.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
